REST API Requirements

By Sergey and Jits

At the moment the following is mainly for Taverna BioCatalogue plugin. The main priority for me is to be able to read the data first. I would like to able to read all the important data about a service (service details, operations along with inputs/outputs and data formats, most important annotations - tags, comments, etc) - this is required to complete the prototype I've shown, make it public and get the feedback on how to start integration with Taverna. When that is done, I'd like to have basic 'write' operations - at the beginning for the annotations (tags, comments, example output data).

Content

Services index — /services.xml :

[DONE] Enrich the services index to provide sufficient data for various listings in applications;

[Jits]: the summary XML document now contains a lot of useful data

[DONE] Include things like service name (already available), provider and very high-level monitoring (e.g. for the “traffic light” icon next to the service);

[Jits]: Not sure about provider. Is this really necessary? Also, provider is associated with a ServiceDeployment.

[DONE] Add related links - for example, link to the summary XML document

Service details — /services/{id}.xml :

[DONE] Inside <versions> element instead of <instance> elements use <soap_instance> and <rest_instance> to show soap/rest service info inline

[Jits]: NOTE: I've “flattened” the <versions> section so that now there is no more the notion of a “ServiceVersion”.

This document should display just the service structure (soap/rest + all operations) – all annotations will be provided in a separate resource which is to be referenced from the <related> section;

Service summary — /services/{id}/summary.xml : The idea of the summary document is to serve as a lightweight fusion of the service structure and simplified collection of annotations. This document has to supply enough information for a quick preview of a service.

[DONE] Add resource URIs to summary (categories, service types, tags, etc)

[Jits]: Not sure what to do with service types, so left that for now.

[DONE] <names> section should have the “main name” and “also known as” names distinguished - otherwise difficult to use

Categories API

[DONE] /categories

[DONE] /categories/{id}

Annotations API

/annotations index (paged + filtered)

Search API

[DONE] Can't combine scope when searching (e.g. need to be able to select 'users' and 'services' at the same time, not just one at a time).

[Jits]: All search strings will be processed using all “special characters” contained in them (e.g. wildcards, etc); to avoid this behaviour and get direct matches (“as is”), search strings need to be quoted. This will allow for proper search for WSDL URLs, etc.

[Sergey]: It could be useful to add rankings to search result items. This way the client will be able to fetch multiple result pages in parallel to get all result set quicker - and rankings will allow to reconstruct the correct ordering of results independently of the order that these parallel requests deliver data to the client.

Lookup API

[DONE] Need a separate API endpoint for 'looking' up known objects by specifying their specific details. E.g. “give me an operation 'getQuery' from WSDL 'http://...'” which will return a concrete object - <soapOperation>..</soapOperation>.

http://sandbox.biocatalogue.org/lookup?...

E.g.:

http://sandbox.biocatalogue.org/lookup.xml?wsdl_location=http://ws.adaptivedisclosure.org/axis/services/IndexWS?wsdl&operation_name=streamContent

Tags API

[DONE] Tag cloud data seems to be present in XML format, but the schema doesn't have details about it.

[DONE] Can't search by tags (e.g. /tags/<tag_name>.xml).

As discussed - only services (and their components) are taggable, but need to have an option to fetch either the actual tagged component or the parent service of that component.

[DONE] With respect to mapping namespaces - we decided to have “namespace” and “name” attributes for each tag with the view to be able to “join” these into a full tag URL somehow.

For /tags.xml:

[DONE] limit returned result count by default;

[DONE] “limit=none” for all tags;

[DONE] remove “none” option from allowed “sort” attribute value list;

[DONE] add pagination of results;

[DONE] higher default page size needed than for services or other objects;

At the moment this is the same as all others (ie: 10) BUT a custom per_page size can be set (max: 50).

add “scope” - parent services or actual tagged objects.

[Jits]: mixing page / page-size and limit is not consistent. Maybe don't need limit? Instead stick with paging metaphors?

Now supports either pagination OR limit (with pagination taking precedence).

For /tag/<tagname>.xml:

In the <related> section add link to filtered list of objects:

[DONE] <taggedServices>

<taggedSoapOperations>

<taggedSoapOperationInputs>

<taggedSoapOperationOutputs>

SOAP Operations/Inputs/Outputs API

[DONE] /soap_operations/{id}

/soap_operations/{id}/annotations

[DONE] /soap_inputs/{id}

/soap_inputs/{id}/annotations

[DONE] /soap_outputs/{id}

/soap_outputs/{id}/annotations

Monitoring API

[DONE] To start with it would be good to have a very basic service state in service summary (and then in service details) document.

[Jits]: there is now a <latestMonitoringStatus> as part of the core elements of <service>.

Service Providers API

[DONE] /service_providers

[DONE] /service_providers/{id}

/service_providers/{id}/annotations

/service_providers/{id}/annotations_by

/service_providers/{id}/services

Registries API

[DONE] /registries

[DONE] /registries/{id}

/registries/{id}/annotations

/registries/{id}/annotations_by

/registries/{id}/services

Users API

[DONE] /users

[DONE] /users/{id}

/users/{id}/annotations_by

/users/{id}/service

Write API

Ideally, all parts of the API should support 'write' operation;

The first priority is to be able to submit annotations of various kinds to existing services (e.g. tags, documentation URLs, sample output data, ports of operations, etc);

Possibly service submission via the API could be useful;

Other

All annotatable resources must have an {resource_type}/{id}/annotations endpoint and subsequent links in main docs

All annotation source resources must have an {resource_type}/{id}/annotations_by endpoint and subsequent links in main docs

[DONE] There's no mention - anywhere in the returned data - of what the actual size of the search results page is (currently it's set to 10). Also, can't request a specific number of items - by this I mean that the results page size could be variable - this way the user could select that 25 results at a time should be fetched, and on request of the next results page the next 25 would be returned (by following a link in the <related> section).

Not all the resources can always be reached by following 'related' links - it would be very useful if a convention existed to aid generation of links within applications. Especially required for filtering and searching. It can be manually done now using 'urlKey' values for filtering, for example.

[Jits - 2009-10-27] Having this type of convention goes against the principles of REST, but there are notable exceptions like for filtering. Could you give examples of resources that cannot be reached by following 'related' links? That way I can add them as related links. In some cases I would have to create a convention (eg: for sorting).

Another requirement is that the content of the XML documents should correspond to the XSD schema, otherwise it is unreachable from applications via automatic binding.

Feature Request Priority

[DONE] Basic monitoring data in the service summary item.

[Jits]: This is now part of core elements of <service>

[DONE] “Lookup” endpoint.

[DONE] Full tags API - I will need to have this in order to finish with the search functionality in the prototype.

[Jits]: I've done most of the things required, except for the taggedOperations, taggedOperationInputs and taggedOperationOutputs.

[DONE] Basic support for retrieving information about users, providers and registries - so that it would be possible to click through to these from the search results.

[DONE] Ability to combine search scopes for regular “search by query”.

[DONE] Ability to get full information about service operations (inputs, outputs, data types, etc).

Annotations API - ability to fetch all available annotations about a service

Write API - ability to contribute service annotations first

For API Documentation

Explain in detail that Services found by tags might be tagged on any their part (e.g. service itself, operations, ports, etc); however, tags on other objects (like operations, ports, etc) would only be 'direct matches' - meaning that it's that object itself which was tagged.

Web Service

Set of functionality that is intended for programmatic access via web technologies.

Operation

Operation relates to units of functionality within the Web Service.

Service Base

In the context of REST Web Services, the longest common shared URI.

Service Endpoint

URI associated with a particular operation of a Web Service.

REST

REST in the context of Web Services is a method of defining the service in a particular way using a type of distributed architecture based on resources.

Resource

In the context of REST. A primitive in the Web Architecture, and is used in the definition of its elements.

A resource is an abstraction of a specific piece of application state or functionality.

An end-point of the URI.

For the purpose of Web Services, actions on Resources are analogous to Operations.

SOAP

A protocol for exchanging XML-based messages over computer networks, normally using HTTP/HTTPS. SOAP forms the foundation layer of the web services protocol stack providing a basic messaging framework upon which abstract layers can be built.

There are two main types of SOAP Web Service encodings:

RPC Encoded

Document Literal

RPC Encoded

A style of SOAP Web Service; a particular way of constructing the content of XML messages, based on not having a schema (unlike in Document Literal, where they are).

Document Literal

A style of SOAP Web Service; the structure of the content of the XML messages is defined by an XML schema.

WSDL

Web Services Description Language, a standard format for describing the interface of SOAP-based Web Services and a certain class of REST Web Services.

Annotation

Annotation is a specific piece of metadata associated with a specific aspect of the Web Service. Annotations may have a type and a context.

Semantic Annotation

Semantic Annotation is a specific piece of metadata associated with a specific aspect of the Web Service. These Annotations are terms from a specific ontology or a controlled vocabulary. They also must have a type and context.

Curation

The act of moderating metadata and annotations often resulting in assertions that either add or agree/dispute existing annotations.

The BioCatalogue Roadmap

Please note that the time scales listed are estimated. New requirements and changes in the user community may affect the delivery dates and schedule.

Fourth quarter of 2008

Private beta - see The Pilot

First quarter of 2009

Public beta - see The Pilot

Advanced search - faceted browsing, filtering and advanced search for services.

Public APIs - simple RESTful APIs to BioCatalogue.

REST services support - ability to register, search and annotate REST services.

Semantic annotation support - ability to annotate service using ontologies.

Second quarter of 2009

Better support for BioMoby services - including semantic annotations from the BioMody registry.

Enhanced search functionality - similarity search and semantic search.

Workflow monitor - monitor services to check whether they are up or down. RSS/ATOM feeds and email notification for monitoring information.

Subscribe to a service - RSS/ATOM feeds for services, providing information on all activity available on a service.

Third quarter 2009

Service usage metrics - usage metrics collection and provider metrics submission. RSS/ATOM feeds and email notifications for these metrics.

Service test functionality - ability to test a service within the BioCatalogue interface before using it.

2010

Set up your own local BioCatalogue registry.

This is the BioCatalogue FAQ … to start, I'll list the questions then assign them to members of the team —

Why BioCatalogue?

While biologist and Bioinformatician find the use of web services critical for their work, they also encounter a number of difficulties associated with the current state of many services and the access to these services. These problems include:

lack of a centralised resources that comprehensively catalogues life science web services thereby making these web services hard to find

the poor documentation or the lack of documentation for many existing web services thereby making them hard to use

lack of effort to improve the quality and coverage of the documentation of these services which means that the documentation if it exist is often out of sync with the current state of the service

lack of information on the quality of services like their availability and reliability

The BioCatalogue is aiming to solve the above-mentioned issues by providing a curated and comprehensive catalogue of biological web services. BioCatalogue will provide a quality of service standard for biological web services thereby enabling services to be classified and checked for availability, reliability and other quality measures. It also aims to provide a platform with several (standardized) interfaces and a suite of tools for registration of services by the community of users as well as empower the community to extend and enhance the system.

Is BioCatalogue free?

The BioCatalogue is an open source project. You can submit, annotate and search for services in BioCatalogue for free. Please read our policy[] for information and guidance. The BioCatalogue source code is also free under the BSD License.

Are the APIs available?

Yes. BioCatalogue has a simple RESTful API and we encourage you to use it. Find the APIs here: []

What are you working on at the moment?

The BioCatalogue team is working on service monitoring, search enhancement, service curation improvement. Have a look a our roadmap[roadmap link] to see what we'll be working on in the coming months.

how do I cite BioCatalogue?

The BioCatalogue can be cited by using the web address http://www.biocatalogue.org/. Biological, medical and technical journals have distinct norms for how citations should be formatted, especially in relation to URLs. Please consult the 'Instruction to Authors' section for further details.

how can I contact you?

BioCatalogue is a user driven project. If you would like to be kept informed about the developement of the project please join our friend list. For bugs report, feedback or feature request email us: biocatalogue-support@rubyforge.org

what type of Web service do you support?

Currently we support SOAP (WSDL type) web services, REST web services, Soaplab services. Support for BioMoby and DAS service is coming soon.

Date: Tuesday 20th Jan 2008

Time: 15:00-16:00 (UK)

Telcon No: 08445805588

Pin: 70503010

Attending

Manchester: Franck, Carole, Steve, David

EBI: Thomas, Eric

Apologies

Rodrigo

Minuting

Eric

Agenda

Franck had a baby! (well, not him exactly, his wife, but you know what I mean)

Actions from the last telcon

Progress with the pilot

Progress of 20 Questions (to clarify user requirements)

Updating the BioCatalogue public wiki and announcement to friends list

Planning for hackathon

AOB

Actions from Previous Meeting

Franck : Provide an example of a semantically annotated service(using the SAWSDL model).

Thomas: investigate 'home' link on the public wiki.

Jits/Thomas/Eric: create developer section on the wiki.

Eric: list the features of the current pilot (including annotations stuff), so that they can be used in a email announcing the private beta to the friends list.

Franck: read through the revised requirements and planning doc and update the private wiki roadmap accordingly. Then after approval copy it to the public wiki.

Franck: make an announcement about latest changes to schedule to the friends list.

Action all : update the 20 questions section on the wiki

Action Rodrigo & Carole : Check the public staging part of the wiki to approve content meant for general public

Action Rodrigo : mail Eric his set of questions to put on the wiki

Action Jits/Thomas/Eric : Plan for effort to spend developing know-how to effectively use solr. Possibly investigate other ways of using the server with/without the acts_as_solr plugin

Action Jits/Eric : Investigate how to add some form of classification of the services

Minutes

There was a discussion on whether it makes sense to tag operations and inputs/outputs. Steve mentioned that in most cases that they have seen in the context of the embrace registry, there is one operation that does the 'task' of the service and other service management operations. Therefore only the tags associated with that 'functional' operation make sense beyond the context of that service. It make sense in the first instance to focus on tagging services and not necessarily operations and inputs/outputs. While there are cases where there are more than a single 'functional' operation within the service envelop, as seen in some DDBJ services, this seems to be the exception. In such cases, it is important to tag the different operations

New Actions

Action David/Carole : Review the wiki pages intended for general public. It is important to free the public wiki of internal terminology

Action Franck : Put up a service classification draft on the wiki

Action all : Add to and/or review the questions on the list of the “20 Questions”

Action Jits/Thomas/Eric/Franck : Prepare for the hackathon in Manchester.

Upcoming Meetings

* Developer F2F at Manchester, week of the 19th

AOB

There will be a demo at the Strategic Advisory Board Meeting in February

There is potential for collaboration with Microsoft. Initial discussions on-going with Carole

Jit doing a presentation on BioCatalogue on the 29th

Previous/Next Meetings

Previous meeting: Phone Conference Meeting on Jan 13 2009

Next meeting: Phone Conference Meeting on Jan 27 2009

Features of the BioCatalogue

Web service discovery

Handles service discovery by keywords or browsing the latest services submitted;

Handles service filtering by tags on services, operations, inputs, and outputs, as well as filtering by providers, submitters, and locations.

Exposes an OpenSearch description document.

Possibility to search the BioCatalogue with your data. Check it out

Possibility to search for individual SOAP operation

Finds similar services given a selected service

Web service annotation

Supports annotation of services by tags, user comments(powered by Disqus) and text description. Annotated services or their parts (operations, inputs, outputs etc) are searchable.

Ability for users to provide many more types of annotations (like examples, name aliases, publication, citations, cost,restrictions, and so on).

Harvests all annotations and services from Feta.

At-a-glance counts of annotations on services (grouped by provider, user and other registries).

Possibility to provide an alternative name for a service and set it as a default display name.

Posssibility to describe the service provider and set a display name

Web service submission

Supports registration for SOAP (WSDL type services)

Supports registration for REST and REST service endpoint

Supports registration for soaplab services.

Web service monitoring

Monitors the WSDL document and enpoints of services

Supports test scripts for automatic test of the functionality of services in the BioCatalogue

Members can archive services no longer in used

Periodically fetches for updates of WSDL documents

Archives deprecated or discontinued operations from the WSDL document

Users

Supports user registration and user profiles for both regular users and service providers.

Supports Service favouriting and rating

Sign in using your regular Google, Yahoo, OpenID OR Facebook account details

BioCatalogue API

To Get Involved

Join our mailing list:
BioCatalogue-Friends Mailing List

Still to come ...

Integration with myExperiment: on the one hand services from BioCatalogue will be displayed in myExperiment so users of myExperiment can browse them. On the other hand services within workflows in myExperiment will reference the appropriate services in BioCatalogue so users can click through to the information in BioCatalogue.

Integration to Taverna: users will be able to import Web Services and annotations to and from BioCatalogue and Taverna. Alpha version released

Public write APIs: Services and annotations submission through the API

myBioCatalogue: setup your private BioCatalogue for your project or organisation

For the list of complete features The Roadmap

Integrating DAS Services into BioCatalogue

About DAS

The DAS registration service provides a repository for registry and discovery of DAS (Distributed Annotation System) services. DAS servers are described with meta data like who is providing a server, what DAS commands are being understood by it, what type of data is being provided, etc. DAS style XML-http as well as SOAP based web services can be used to interact with the DAS registry. This is used by DAS clients like EnsEMBL, SPICE, or Dasty to retrieve the list of available services.

More information about a DAS registry can be found here

Registry Sources Interface

The DAS registry can return an xml representation of all the sources(services) in the DAS registry. The sources currently available in the DAS registry can be accessed here. We can parse this xml file to register DAS services in BioCatalogue

Importing DAS services into BioCatalogue

It appears that it would be better to sync with the DAS registry periodically and not to allow individual DAS sources to be registered (Though since DAS sources are rest services, one could argue that they may be registered as rest services). This would mean that when things are added/deleted from the DAS registry, they will also be add/deleted from the BioCatalogue during the next sync process.

Format of DAS source XML

The DAS sources xml file could contain a number of DAS sources with the source having a format as below

<SOURCES>
  <SOURCE uri="DS_111" title="cath" doc_href="http://cathdb.info" description="The CATH database annotates PDB  structures with CATH structural domains  as derived from a combination of  automatic and manually methods.">
    <MAINTAINER email="sillitoe@biochem.ucl.ac.uk" />
    <VERSION uri="DS_111" created="2005-03-21T16:30:26+0000">
      <COORDINATES uri="http://www.dasregistry.org/dasregistry/coordsys/CS_DS7" source="Protein Structure" authority="PDBresnum" test_range="5pti">PDBresnum,Protein Structure</COORDINATES>
      <CAPABILITY type="das1:features" query_uri="http://cathdb.info:9000/das/cath_pdb/features" />
      <PROP name="label" value="BioSapiens" />
      <PROP name="label" value="eFamily" />
      <PROP name="leaseTime" value="2010-11-18T07:56:59+0000" />
      <PROP name="projectHome" value="http://www.biosapiens.info" />
      <PROP name="projectIcon" value="http://www.dasregistry.org/ProjectIcon?id=74" />
      <PROP name="projectDesc" value="BioSapiens is a Network of Excellence, funded by the European Union's 6th Framework Programme, and made up of bioinformatics researchers from 25 institutions based in 14 countries throughout Europe.

The objective of the BioSapiens is to provide a large" />
      <PROP name="projectName" value="BioSapiens" />
      <PROP name="spec" value="DAS/1.53E" />
      <PROP name="sources" value="invalid" />
      <PROP name="features" value="valid" />
      <PROP name="types" value="invalid" />
    </VERSION>
  </SOURCE>
<SOURCES>

From the BioCatalogue side, a parser would be required for the DAS xml.

Effect on BioCatalogue Data Model

Following the pattern which is already being used, it would make sense(actually required) to extend the BioCatalogue model with the DAS service type. This would minimize the impact on the current model and allow annotations to be layered on the DAS services in much the same way as they are done on REST/SOAP service types. What attributes would be made annotatable may be determined later after discussion with the DAS people.

Monitoring

Availability monitoring for the DAS services can be done in much the same way as for REST services. The resource URI would be checked for availability in the same way that other urls are being check at the moment.

Summary

The main requirements identified for the integration of DAS services are :

Parser for parsing the DAS sources xml

Extension of the BioCatalogue data model to take care of DAS specific attributes

Extension of the Availability monitoring to include DAS endpoints( sources )

Extension of the service updates mechanism to refresh DAS services

Testing of the DAS extensions to the application

An approximate estimate for this work would be about a (man) calendar month.

Below are the publications made by the BioCatalogue team, the citations for the BioCatalogue and the articles about the BioCatalogue.

Publications

Gaudet P, Bairoch A, Field D, Sansone SA, Taylor C, Attwood TK, Bateman A, Blake JA, Bult CJ, Cherry JM, Chisholm RL, Cochrane G, Cook CE, Eppig JT, Galperin MY, Gentleman R, Goble CA, Gojobori T, Hancock JM, Howe DG, Imanishi T, Kelso J, Landsman D, Lewis SE, Karsch Mizrachi I, Orchard S, Ouellette BF, Ranganathan S, Richardson L, Rocca-Serra P, Schofield PN, Smedley D, Southan C, Tan TW, Tatusova T, Whetzel PL, White O, Yamasaki C; on behalf of the BioDBCore working group. Towards BioDBcore: a community-defined information specification for biological databases, in Database (2011) Vol. 2011 published online January 4, 2011, doi:10.1093/database/baq027 and Nucl. Acids Res. (2011) 39 (suppl 1) D7-D10 1 January 2011 doi: 10.1093/nar/gkq1173 http://nar.oxfordjournals.org/content/39/suppl_1/D7.full.pdf+html

Jiten Bhagat; Franck Tanoh; Eric Nzuobontane; Thomas Laurent; Jerzy Orlowski; Marco Roos; Katy Wolstencroft; Sergejs Aleksejevs; Robert Stevens; Steve Pettifer; Rodrigo Lopez; Carole A. Goble BioCatalogue: a universal catalogue of web services for the life sciences Nucleic Acids Research 2010, 38 (suppl 2): W689-W694. Featured paper doi: 10.1093/nar/gkq394

Paolo Missier, Katy Wolstencroft, Franck Tanoh, Peter Li, Sean Bechhofer, Khalid Belhajjame, Steve Pettifer, Carole Goble. Functional Units: Abstractions for Web Service Annotations presented at IEEE 2010 Fourth International Workshop on Scientific Workflows (SWF 2010). Abstract Full paper: the_functional_units_paper.pdf

Goble CA and De Roure D Curating Scientific Web Services and Workflows EDUCAUSE Review, vol. 43, no. 5 (September/October 2008)http://eprints.ecs.soton.ac.uk/16561/

Goble CA, Stevens RD, Hull D, Wolstencroft K, Lopez R Data Curation + Process Curation = Data Integration + Science, Briefings in Bioinformatics, 2008 http://bib.oxfordjournals.org/cgi/content/short/bbn034v1?rss=1

Khalid Belhajjame, Carole Goble, Franck Tanoh, et al. Biocatalogue: A Curated Web Service Registry for the Life Science Community, Microsoft eScience conference 2008. biocatalogue_position_paper.pdf and 3rd Intl Conference of BioCurators, published in Nature Precedings, April 2009 http://precedings.nature.com/documents/3132/version/1

Citations

1. Damian Smedley et al., in their paper, Finding and sharing: new approaches to registries of databases and services for the biomedical sciences emphasized the usefulness of the BioCatalogue for the community and advocated the use of the registry by all service providers to publish their services.

2. Achille Zappa, Mariangela Miele and Paolo Romano in their paper IBWS: IST Bioinformatics Web Services present their web services submitted in the BioCatalogue.

3. Javier Ríos and colleagues mention in their paper, Magallanes: a web services discovery and automatic workflow composition tool, the need to integrate Magallanes and the BioCatalogue.

4. Michael Gruenberge et al., in their paper, Towards the integration of mouse databases - definition and implementation of solutions to two use-cases in mouse functional genomics, favor the idea to submit to the BioCatalogue any web services developed during the course of their project.

5. Victoria Martín-Requenaw et al., reference the BioCatalogue in their paper, jORCA: easily integrating bioinformatics Web Services

6. María Pérez et al., propose a Semi-Discovery approach of Web service which heavily relies on the BioCatalogue service category classification. The paper is: Semi-automatic Discovery of Web Services Driven by User Requirements

7. BioCatalogue is cited in this paper: Protein structure analysis of mutations causing inheritable diseases. An e-Science approach with life scientist friendly interfaces; by Hanka Venselaar et al.

8. Hammad Afzal, James Eales, Robert Stevens and Goran Nenadic. Mining semantic networks of bioinformatics e-resources from the literature http://www.jbiomedsem.com/content/2/S1/S4 in the Journal of Biomedical Semantics 2011.

9. Paolo Missier, Norman Paton and Peter Li. Workflows for Information Integration in the Life Sciences in Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 2011, Volume 6585/2011, 215-225, DOI: 10.1007/978-3-642-19668-3_20

10. Jia Zhang, Wei Tan, John Alexander, Ian Foster, Ravi Madduri . Recommend-As-You-Go: A Novel Approach Supporting Services-Oriented Scientific Workflow Reuse. IEEE Intl Conf on Services Computing (SCC), 2011 (Best Paper Award)

11. Jia Zhang, Ravi Madduri, Wei Tan, Kevin Deichl, John Alexander, Ian Foster. Toward Semantics Empowered Biomedical Web Services. IEEE Intl Conf on Web Services (ICWS), 2011

12. Wei Tan, Jia Zhang, Ian Foster. Network Analysis of Scientific Workflows: a Gateway to Reuse. IEEE Computer, 43(9): 54-61, 2010. doi:10.1109/MC.2010.2622010

Articles

1. BioCatalogue: The 'Yellow Pages' of web services, an article by Marco Roos published on the Netherlands Bioinformatics Centre (NBIC) website.

2. A cool BioCatalogue introduction video on the OpenHelix Blog by Mary Mangan

3. BioCatalogue mentioned by David De Roure in his article e-Science and the Web in IEEE Computer Society publications

4. BioCatalogue article in the OMII-UK newsletter by Franck Tanoh

5. BioCatalogue article in genomeweb by Vivien Marx

6. BioCatalogue slides and presentations are here

7. BioCatalogue on wikipedia

8. ChEMBL Web Services are now in BioCatalogue

Meeting Agenda/Minutes

Date: Tuesday 28th October 2008

Time: 15:00-17:00 (UK)

Attending

Manchester: Franck, Jits

EBI: Rodrigo, Eric

Apologies

Carole, Hamish, Thomas, Katy

Minuting

Agenda

Action from the last telcon.

Progress with the pilot - are we rolling?

Annual Report - are we rolling?

BioCatalogue public wiki

AOB.

Actions from Previous Meeting

Jits: Speak to Dave about the new privacy policy in myExperiment. We'll use EBI privacy policy.

Action Thomas : Create a public space on BioCatalogue wiki …Done.

Action Eric, Jits, Thomas, Franck : Establish the list of features for the pilot and road map for future development

feature for the pilot…section 3.2 and 3.3 to be completed for the report.

Action Thomas : Configure the mailer on the BioCatalogue beta site …done, the site is: beta.biocatalogue.org

Action Eric : Investigate Biomoby script from Eddie…done. Eric thinks that we should extend current model for service group (by providers).

Action Carole : Complete Annual Report: still section 3.2 and 3.3 to be completed..

Action Robert : Organize the advisory board meeting. Could be at EBI or Manchester and would be desirable for the whole team to be there… could be anywhere hopefully not in the middle of november.

Eric & Thomas: set up pilot.biocatalogue.org and deploy the current work on the pilot…done.

Minutes

Progress with the pilot - are we rolling?

Slower than expected but we're getting there. By next week we should have the minimum functionality ready.

Annual Report - are we rolling?

Section 3.2 and 3.3 to be completed by Franck, Jits, Eric.

BioCatalogue public wiki

Need to keep it simple at this stage with 2 majors items:

    where do we come from?(content from the website)
    where are we going? (roadMap)

New Actions

Eric: read EBI privacy policy and make sure we have a version appropriate for BioCatalogue

Rodrigo: add content to the public wiki

Upcoming Meetings

Semantic Web Applications and Tools for Life Sciences - 28/11/08 http://www.swat4ls.org/

AOB

Previous/Next Meetings

Previous meeting:Phone Conference Meeting on Oct 14 2008

Next meeting: Phone Conference Meeting on Nov 04 2008